intheknowtraveler.com 2006-07-17

# Privacy Statement at In the Know Traveler

In The Know Traveler is concerned with protecting the privacy of all its visitors. We want you to be able to browse our site, join our newsletters and make use of our public forums without being bothered by unwanted spam and solicitors. We know there is normally some confusing jargon using technical terms concerning this privacy but we are not lawyers. We are writers. We want to be understood. We also hope your visit to our sites are fun, informative and problem free without any concerns about unwanted electronic intrusion. So here is our privacy statement in is in the simplest of terms: we do not collect personal information about you. The only time this ever changes is because you wrote us and requested contact, you have joined one of our newsletters or we are hiring and need specific information pertaining to contract work. If this answer is not enough please read on and if there is something we didn’t cover, please [write us](mailto:questions@intheknowtraveler.com). 

In The Know Traveler never obtains personally-identifying information about you when you visit our site. This changes only if you want to become a registered user or to subscribe to our newsletter, which will require your email address. In this case, any information we obtain will never be sold, rented, or otherwise transferred to any third party for any reason. Furthermore, if you are a registered member or newsletter subscriber, any information we collect to process your registration or subscription will not be sold, rented or loaned to anyone, ever. 

**What we keep track of**  
If you visit our site, we collect and store only the following information about you: 

  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet; 
  * The date and time you access our site 
  * The Internet address of the website you used to link directly to our site.

I’m not sure why we do this. But there is a guy, a web master guy who needs it to help us better serve you. Please read on. What do you use the data for? The web master guy likes to tell us how people find us and how often they find us. Hopefully, a lot people find us and keep coming back. Then, there is some software he uses that breaks down all the information. Much of the statistical information goes over our heads but we use what we understand to provide you with the best content and articles that you are hopefully most interested in reading about. 

**Purchasing from In The Know Traveler**  
If you buy something from one of our affiliated vendors through intheknowtraveler.com, the vendor may offer information to us regarding the sale for commission tracking and statistical purposes. The vendor may also use the data for its own tracking and statistical purposes because they have their own webmaster guy. For more information on vendors’ privacy policies, please contact them directly. 

**Is there any other kind of personal data you might use?**  
If you write us and ask us a question we are going to write you back with the address you supplied. Similarly, if you write to us to be connected to one of our affiliates then we will send the address to them but we only do this at your request.What about affiliated businesses and organizations? Our hope is that all business and organizations affiliated with intheknowtraveler.com will maintain the same strict guidelines for protecting the anonymity of all our users. Unfortunately, intheknowtraveler.com is not a supervisory agent or governing organization, listing businesses may use information gathered from you at their own site for their own purposes because they have their own web master guy. If you are concerned about what other businesses do with the information they receive about you, please contact them directly.

**Is there an exception to the rule?**  
Yes. Theoretically, we could be required, by law, to turn over any obtained information to law enforcement or other governmental agencies, or if the personal information is relevant in a legal proceeding or court action. 

**Public Forums**  
Intheknowtraveler.com will provide forums so registered members may ask questions and receive information about travel and related topics. We recommend never posting personal information about yourself or anyone else at any time on these forums or anywhere else on the web. 

**Email**  
Registered users will receive occasional newsletters that may contain promotional offers from advertisers and affiliate businesses. Advertisers and sponsors will not contact you directly. Remember, all registered members and subscribers may “opt out” from receiving emails and newsletters from us, for any reason, at any time.

**Questions**  
If you have questions or comments about this privacy statement or any information posted on our web site, feel free to contact us at [questions@intheknowtraveler.com](mailto:questions@intheknowtraveler.com).
